# **Cong Nguyen Tran**

Software Engineer

0395714940

Ngu Hanh Son, Da Nang, Viet Nam

# **BACKGROUND/CAREER OBJECTIVES**

I have three years of experience working as a web and mobile developer. Javascript, PHP, Dart, Swift, MongoDB, Graphql and etc, and the eco-system around them, such as Typescript, NodeJS, Vue, React, Flutter and Laravel are programming languages that I can use to develop projects. I started working in this field as a freelancer when I was studying at university. During that time, I created a big project at the top of Vietnam's traffic for many years.

# WORK EXPERIENCE -

#### **Freelancer**

2019 - 01/2022

## **TaGiVi**

02/2021 - 11/2021

# Codeby

01/2022 - 04/2022

# **Smileeye Education**

04/2022 - 12/2022

## **FULLSTACK DEVELOPER**

- Find and approach customers on social networks.
- Give some advice to clients about technology, budget, and advertisements for their products
- Conduct development of the project following the clients' requirements.
- Maintain projects and create new features following client's requirements.

# **FULLSTACK DEVELOPER**

- Create a novel platform including three websites and a mobile application.
- Monitor the database performance.
- Participate in planning and running several advertising campaigns to promote the platform.
- Evaluate the client's review of the Apple store to improve the mobile application performance.

# **FULLSTACK DEVELOPER**

- Create and customize WordPress plugins.
- Using Vuejs to create complex components to embed into WordPress website.
- Improving the SEO efficiency of the website.

# **FULLSTACK DEVELOPER**

- Collaborate with other employees to develop an educational platform.
- Create a video call application to help students connect with each other.
- · Improve some existing projects of the company.
- Planning with the company to host an event at the university for marketing the educational product.

## **PROJECTS**

# Fancuongboylove

01/2019 - 02/2019

Name of customer Anonymous

Team size 2

# TaGiVi

02/2019 - 11/2019

Name of customer Tung

Team size 3

# Mitingu

07/ 2022 - 10/2022

Name of customer

Dong Phuong

Team size 2

# Smile

03/ 2022 - 12/2023

Name of customer

Dong Phuong

Team size 2

## **DEVELOPER FULLSTACK**

- Create two websites through Laravel and VueJS.
- Backup and transfer the database to the new product.
- Connect Imgur API to store images for free.

#### **TECHNOLOGY DESCRIPTION**

Laravel, VueJS, MySQL.

#### **DEVELOPER FULLSTACK**

- Using Vuejs to develop websites and mobile applications via Flutter.
- Using MongoDB and Websocket to store the data and combine with Redis to improve the backend performance.
- Apply Graphql architecture to enhance the flexibility and security of the backend.

## **TECHNOLOGY DESCRIPTION**

ExpressJS, MongoDB, Redis, Graphql, VueJS, Nuxt, Flutter, Firebase.

## **DEVELOPER FRONTEND DEVELOPER**

• Take advantage of Agora API, Vuejs, and Firebase to create a video call application.

## **TECHNOLOGY DESCRIPTION**

NestJS, Agora, Nuxt 3, Firebase.

# **DEVELOPER FRONTEND DEVELOPER**

- Develop some parts of the primary project.
- Give some advice to the backend team to improve the overall application performance.

## **TECHNOLOGY DESCRIPTION**

ReactJS, Vite, Grahql, Firebase.

# **EDUCATION**

2019 - 2023

# **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Dong A University

Faculty of Information Technology

## SKILLS

## Manage team

Lead a team of freelancers to meet client requirements.

# **Absorb A New Technology**

Have the ability to learn a new programming language quickly.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

## KEF

# **DECEMBER 5, 2022**

**Duolingo English Test** 

- GitHub: https://github.com/nguyenshort
- Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/nguyenshort98/

# **PROJECT ARTICLES -**

- $\bullet \ https://www.saostar.vn/sao-va-doi-song/ta-gi-vi-website-truyen-cua-tac-gia-viet-202103251743545241.html$
- https://www.yan.vn/tagivi-noi-bat-voi-kho-tang-truyen-da-dang-thu-vi-day-tinh-thoi-su-261944.html

© topcv.vn